export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A literary work which is intended to teach a moral lesson is __________",
A: "romantic",
B: "didactic",
C: "mimetic",
D: "moralistic.",
answer: "B. didactic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A short account of an interesting event is ________",
A: "a tale.",
B: "an anecdote",
C: "an episode.",
D: "a story",
answer: "B. anecdote",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. He is a citizen of no mean city illustrates _________",
A: "bathos",
B: "euphemism",
C: "metonymy",
D: "litotes",
answer: "D. litotes (understatement)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The introductory part of a play, a novel or a poem is the ________",
A: "epilogue",
B: "plot",
C: "setting",
D: "prologue",
answer: "D. prologue",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An elegy is a poem of ________",
A: "mourning",
B: "complain",
C: "hope",
D: "joy",
answer: "A. mourning",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The trees bowed their heads in shame illustrates _______",
A: "personification",
B: "alliteration",
C: "assonance",
D: "paradox",
answer: "A. personification",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A character whose actions are predictable in a literary work is _________",
A: "round characte",
B: "a flat character",
C: "the hero",
D: "the villain",
answer: "B. a flat character",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A scene in fiction enacting past events is __________",
A: "allusion",
B: "foreshadow",
C: "flashback",
D: "interlude",
answer: "C. flashback",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Poetic licence is a term applied to a poet's _______",
A: "choice of word",
B: "choice of characters",
C: "restrictions in the use of language",
D: "freedom in the use of language",
answer: "D. freedom in the use of language",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Milton! thou should'st be living at this hour. The literary device used in the line above is _________",
A: "aside",
B: "apostrophe",
C: "soliloquy",
D: "suspense",
answer: "B. apostrophe (Addressing Milton directly)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Here lie I, Martin Eliginbrodde Have mercy on my soul, Lord Gọd The extract above illustrates ______",
A: "epitaph",
B: "elegy",
C: "ballad",
D: "dirge",
answer: "A. epitaph",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. We live to die, we die to live is an example of _________",
A: "paradox",
B: "hyperbole",
C: "inversion",
D: "Oxymoron",
answer: "A. paradox",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The poem is about a/an ___________",
A: "flower",
B: "old woman",
C: "little child",
D: "traveller",
answer: "C. little child",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The persona's mood is one of ________",
A: "anger",
B: "admiration",
C: "indifference",
D: "joy",
answer: "B. admiration",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The, thyme pattern is ______",
A: "abc abc",
B: "aa bb cc",
C: "ab ab cc",
D: "aa bc bc",
answer: "B. aa bb cc",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A play in which characters act through gestures and facial expressions is a _______",
A: "pantomime",
B: "burlesque",
C: "melodrama",
D: "farce",
answer: "A. pantomime",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Characterization refers to __________",
A: "how characters are grouped",
B: "the readers' opinions of the characters",
C: "how characters are depicted",
D: "the roles played by the character",
answer: "C. how characters are depicted",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In a literary work, the foil is one who ________",
A: "Complements another character",
B: "contrasts with another character",
C: "introduces the conflict",
D: "resolves the conflict",
answer: "B. contrasts with another character",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Dramatis personae refers to ________",
A: "audience",
B: "characters",
C: "chorus",
D: "cast",
answer: "D. cast",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A literary' device used to enhance sound effect in poetry is __________",
A: "imagery",
B: "alliteration",
C: "refrain",
D: "symbol",
answer: "B. alliteration",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. ...supine eyes ... illustrates _______",
A: "oxymoron",
B: "paradox",
C: "verbal irony",
D: "synecdoche.",
answer: "C. Anxiety",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Rumbling as used in the 1st paragraph is ______",
A: "onomatopoeic",
B: "metaphoric",
C: "ironic",
D: "alliterative",
answer: "B. Visual images (e.g., 'death smelled in the air')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The dominant theme is ______",
A: "unrequited love",
B: "loss of opportunity",
C: "lack of trust.",
D: "insatiable hunger",
answer: "B. Litotes (Understatement: 'Their silence spoke millions' - meaning their silence conveyed immense worry)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The narrative technique is ________",
A: "third person",
B: "first person",
C: "interior-monologue",
D: "multiple narration.",
answer: "B. Personification (Giving the bell the human action of 'summoning')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The writer's attitude is one of ________",
A: "anger",
B: "indifference",
C: "sympathy",
D: "mockery",
answer: "A. In First person ('I' is the narrator)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The stanzas are written in _________",
A: "quintets",
B: "quatrains",
C: "sestets",
D: "tercets",
answer: "C. Quatrain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The recurrent device used is ________",
A: "synecdoche",
B: "apostrophe",
C: "metonymy",
D: "paradox",
answer: "C. Sight and Hearing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The mood of the poet is ________",
A: "derisive",
B: "ecstatic",
C: "regretful",
D: "melancholic",
answer: "B. Repetition ('rest awhile' is repeated)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The opening lines of the stanzas are ________",
A: "trochaic",
B: "iambic",
C: "anapaestic",
D: "dactylic",
answer: "C. Nostalgia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The first stanza rhymes ______",
A: "ab ac",
B: "ab ab",
C: "abcb",
D: "abba",
answer: "C. Synecdoche ('ears will drink' - using a part to represent the whole)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is ___________",
A: "Gratiano",
B: "Duke",
C: "Lodovico",
D: "Montano",
answer: "A. Duke",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The speech is directly addressed to __________",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Brabantio",
C: "Othello",
D: "2nd Senator",
answer: "B. Brabantio",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The speech is about ________",
A: "Brabantio's complaint about Othello.",
B: "Othello's loss of his handkerchief",
C: "Brabantio's loss of his daughter",
D: "the fight between Cassio and Roderigo",
answer: "C. Othello's war exploits",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. By the speech, the speaker attempts to __________",
A: "instigate the addressee",
B: "console the addressee",
C: "prevent a war",
D: "settle a fight",
answer: "D. Make the best out of this (Accept the situation gracefully)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The underlined expression means ________",
A: "one is bound to lose something in life",
B: "keep smiling even while being robbed",
C: "it is useful not to bemoan one's loss",
D: "the thief loses either way",
answer: "A. The tale was good enough to win a woman's heart",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker and the addrešsee are ___________",
A: "Lodovico and Roderigo",
B: "Clown and Lodovico",
C: "lago and Roderigo",
D: "lago and Clown.",
answer: "C. lago and Roderigo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. What binds the speaker and addressee together is their _______",
A: "hatred for Othello",
B: "fear of Cassio",
C: "fear of Cassio",
D: "hatred for Brabantio",
answer: "A. hatred for Othello",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The addressee is enjoined to Go, make money for ___________",
A: "wooing Desdemona",
B: "enriching lago",
C: "placating Brabantio",
D: "rewarding Bianca",
answer: "B. enriching lago",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The underlined expression means ________",
A: "you have your way by making him angry",
B: "you gain ty making his wite",
C: "you will not be delighted at the result",
D: "you will have succeeded in seducing her",
answer: "D. you will have succeeded in seducing her",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The speaker's attitude to the addressee is one of ________",
A: "spite",
B: "envy",
C: "friendliness",
D: "intolerance",
answer: "C. friendliness (though insincere)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The speaker is __________",
A: "Othello",
B: "Gratiano",
C: "lago",
D: "Cassio",
answer: "A. Othello",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The setting is ___________",
A: "a street in front of the citadel",
B: "a street",
C: "the citadel",
D: "Desdemona's chamber",
answer: "C. the citadel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The speaker is addressing _________",
A: "Duke and others",
B: "Emilia",
C: "the Senate",
D: "Lodovico and others",
answer: "D. Lodovico and others",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The speech is intended to _______",
A: "preserve the speaker's reputation",
B: "express the speakers remorse",
C: "express the speaker's acceptance of guilt",
D: "denounce the speaker's enemies",
answer: "C. express the speaker's acceptance of guilt",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Among these unlucky deeds. the immediate one is _________",
A: "he killing of Desdemona",
B: "declaring Desdemiona as unfaithful",
C: "refusing to listen to Emilia",
D: "the sacking of Cassio",
answer: "A. he killing of Desdemona",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The speaker is ________",
A: "Brabantio",
B: "Othello",
C: "Duke",
D: "Montano",
answer: "B. Othello",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The occasion is _________",
A: "Othello's return from war",
B: "Othello's departure for Cyprus",
C: "Montano expressirig his delight after the tempest.",
D: "the defeat of the Turks.",
answer: "B. Othello's departure for Cyprus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The dominant images are associated with _______",
A: "love",
B: "nature",
C: "sailing",
D: "war",
answer: "C. sailing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The scene reveals the speaker's __________",
A: "fear of adventure",
B: "affection for his wife",
C: "suspicion",
D: "fulfilment as a warrior",
answer: "D. fulfilment as a warrior",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The language of the extract is best described as _________",
A: "ironical",
B: "humorous",
C: "hyperbolical",
D: "sarcástie.",
answer: "C. hyperbolical",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]